You and your family used to live around here too, right?
你和你的家人也在这里生活过吧？
I never
我再也…
want to lose you two again.
不想失去你们了
Remember, I cannot tell a lie.
毕竟 我无法说谎
Crypto's crashed and I've lost it all.
加密货币崩盘了 我全输光了
I want to stop him.
我想阻止他
It's not even about beating him.
重点已经不是要打败他了
You're the only one who can do it.
只有你能做到
I don't care about coming in first anymore.
我已经不在乎是否能当第一了
I've found something even more important than that.
我找到了更重要的事
THE HONEST REALTOR 2
电视剧名：正直不动产2
FINAL EPISODE HONEST REALTOR FOREVER
第10集：永远的正直不动产
Here, Mr. Nagase. Come say something.
永濑前辈 你快来说说他
What's up?
怎么了？
He's investing in crypto on company time again.
十影又利用上班时间投资加密货币了
Come on, Tokage. Don't do that.
好了 十影 别弄了
Mr. Nagase, a reprimand doesn't work if you do it with a smile.
永濑前辈 笑着训斥人能有用吗？
You guys shooting the breeze? Come on, back to work.
你们在聊天吗？赶紧回去工作
Why is everyone smiling through their anger?
怎么部长也笑着发怒？
What do you mean? This is just my resting face.
说什么呢？我又不是竹中直人
"I got my eye on you."
“我盯着你们呢”
I don't quite get it, but okay.
我不太明白 但没关系
Did something good happen?
发生了什么好事吗？
Could it be because Minerva has now called off the attack?
会不会是因为 密涅瓦不动产如今主动停战了
Well, that was good too, but nothing like this. Right, Nagase?
那确实是好事 但比不上这个 对吧 永濑？
-It's been a long time coming. -Yep.
-我们筹备好久了 -确实
A long time coming?
筹备已久？
A six-year-long project of ours is finally going to see the light of day.
我们筹备了六年的一个项目 终于要迎来曙光了
-It nearly broke us. -Now you're crying?
-差点把我们折腾崩溃 -居然哭了？
It's been so long.
太久了
It has.
确实
What kind of project is it?
究竟是什么项目？
It's a large-scale development to bring together 20,000 tsubo of land.
是个大规模土地开发项目 覆盖面积超过6.5万平米
MUSASHIMURAYAMA CITY, KASAHARA DISTRICT
（武藏村山市笠原地区 物流仓库建设计划）
-20,000 tsubo? -It all started six years ago.
-6.5万平米？ -一切都始于六年前
LARGE-SCALE DEVELOPMENT
（大规模开发）
LOGISTICS WAREHOUSE CONSTRUCTION PLAN
（物流仓库建设计划）
TOKYO METROPOLIS &amp; MUSASHIMURAYAMA CITY
（东京都 武藏村山市）
Mr. Tosaka teamed up with a large-scale builder
登坂社长与一家大型建筑商联手
to combine 20,000 tsubo of land into one plot in Musashimurayama City,
想整合武藏村山市 一片6.5万平米的土地
with the view to build a warehouse to sell on to a major real estate agency.
修建一个仓库 卖给一家大型房地产中介公司
The builder is going to purchase the land for four billion yen,
建筑商将以40亿日元的价格 买下这块地
do their construction work,
完成施工
and then sell the result to a large real estate agency for 8.8 billion yen.
然后把成品以88亿日元的价格 卖给一家大型房地产中介公司
Our role in all of this
我们在其中扮演的角色是
was to broker the transactions between the leaseholders and the builder.
在拥有土地的地权人和建筑商之间 牵线搭桥 促成交易
We made around 260 million on those brokerage fees alone.
仅中介费就能赚取2.6亿
Over 200 million? That's a lot.
超过两亿？这可不是小数
Development's finally received the official go-ahead,
如今开发终于获得了官方批准
so we're getting close to finally closing the contract.
我们很快就能最终敲定合同了
It's been such an ordeal.
太不容易了
DEVELOPMENT APPROVAL
（开发同意书）
We had to get the consent of all 80 rural leaseholders.
一共涉及80位农村地权人 必须让他们全员同意
ALLOTMENT MAP
（分布图）
Come rain or shine, sleet or snow,
无论刮风下雨、严寒酷暑
we did the rounds, getting approval after approval.
我们跑了一趟又一趟 挨家挨户征求同意
And after all that back-breaking labor, we're finally getting our just deserts.
经过那么多辛劳 我们终于要得到应有的回报了 永濑
Mr. Okawa.
部长
We did good. We did good.
太好了 我们真棒
We worked so hard.
我们付出了那么多努力
We worked so hard for so long.
而且努力了那么长时间
Go on. Cry it out.
哭吧 尽情哭
MUSASHIMURAYAMA CITY, KASAHARA DISTRICT
（武藏村山市笠原地区 物流仓库建设计划）
ALLOTMENT MAP
（分布图）
My legs…
想想我可怜的腿…
Day in, day out. So many expenses to get reimbursed…
日复一日 还有那么多费用需要报销
What an amazing spread.
太厉害了吧
What's the occasion?
今天是什么日子？
We've had a breakthrough in a large project of ours,
我们的一个大项目取得了突破性进展
and I'm really happy about it.
我实在太开心
I see.
原来如此
That's good news.
太好了
When this project's all done and dusted, I have something important to tell you.
等项目尘埃落定 我有很重要的事想告诉你
Something important?
很重要的事？
I'll tell you later.
到时候再说
For now, let's eat.
现在先吃饭吧
Sure.
好
You want me to move?
您想把我调去别的地方？
To New York?
去纽约？
Well, this is unexpected.
这真是太意外了
If it were me, I'd take it in a heartbeat.
如果是我 绝对眼都不眨就会同意
LOGISTICS WAREHOUSE CONSTRUCTION PLAN
（物流仓库建设计划）
This 20,000 tsubo plot of land
这片6.5万平米的土地
is supposedly getting a giant warehouse built on top of it.
计划要修建一个巨型仓库
MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不动产）
So that's what it is.
原来如此
Some idle cropland.
好一片闲置农地
AGRICULTURAL LAND NOT CURRENTLY IN USE
（目前闲置的农田）
How did you find this out?
你是怎么发现这事的？
This Tosaka project is six years in the making.
登坂不动产为此准备了整整六年
I'm thinking any setbacks would be fatal.
我认为任何阻碍都足以致命
Sir, I think you should stop going after Tosaka Real Estate.
社长 我觉得您 不该再盯着登坂不动产不放了
You have more important things to do.
您还有更重要的事
You can quit right now if you refuse to follow my lead.
如果你不肯听我的指挥 现在就可以辞职
I'll leave this matter
这件事
with you, Kamiki.
就交给神木了
Thank you, sir.
谢谢社长
IDLE CROPLAND
（闲置农地）
It's so big.
好大
(PROPOSED CONSTRUCTION SITE OF LOGISTICS WAREHOUSE)
（物流仓库建设预定地）
20,000 tsubo. That's bigger than Tokyo Dome.
6.5万平米 比东京巨蛋体育场还大
It's pretty infested with weeds for supposed farm land.
不过 既然是农田 这里怎么杂草丛生？
Out of the 80 householders here,
这里的80户人家
most struggled when they inherited the farm and just let it go over time.
大部分在继承了农田后都难以为继 渐渐就让其闲置了
I guess you can only really sell farming land to other farmers, can't you?
我还以为农地只能卖给其他农民 不是吗？
That's right.
的确
And converting agricultural land to anything else is a whole process.
将农地转作其他任何用途 都需要克服重重困难
REPURPOSING FARMING LAND FOR OTHER USES
（将农地转作他用）
I have heard of that.
我听说过
PERMISSION GRANTED TO CONVERT AGRICULTURAL LAND
（农用土地改造许可标识）
You have to get permission from the Agricultural Affairs Committee,
必须先得到农业事务委员会的许可
and find a developer and get developmental approval from the government.
然后要找到开发商 还要拿到政府许可
Mr. Tosaka and Mr. Okawa took care of all the legal stuff.
社长和大河部长搞定了一切法律事务
They say the government only grants one development project per year…
据说政府每年只放行一个开发项目…
CITY COUNCILLORS A &amp; B
（市议会议员 A和B）
…so there's a long waiting list.
…所以排队名单非常长
Mr. Tosaka laid all the groundwork for us,
社长人脉广泛 帮我们打好了一切基础
but as for the clincher…
至于锁定胜局的…
You didn't go to any of the dinners?
那些应酬永濑先生一次都没去吗？
No, I was in charge of securing the 80 leaseholders.
对 我当时负责搞定那80户人家
Eighty.
80户
How'd you do it for 80 households?
你怎么搞定了80户人家？
MUSASHIMURAYAMA WAREHOUSE PLAN MARCH 2018 ONWARDS
（武藏村山市仓库建设计划 2018年3月-）
-With this. -What is it?
-靠这个 -这是什么？
It contains all the personal information on the leaseholders.
这里面包含了所有地权人的个人信息
I used their hobbies and their favorite foods to make them come around.
我投其所好 并用他们喜爱的美食 赢得了他们的同意
It's all in here.
都在这里
This right here was a lifesaver for the project.
这东西是这项目的救命稻草
That's amazing!
好厉害
-I really busted my butt. -Wait.
-我可太努力了 -等等
-Can I see it? -No, you cannot.
-能给我看看吗？ -不行
I need you to get that notebook for me.
我需要你帮我弄到那个笔记本
You mean steal it?
你是想让我去偷？
I'll give you a million.
我给你一百万
-But-- -Five million.
-可是… -五百万
Five million?
五百万？
You lost a lot on crypto, right?
你玩加密货币输了不少吧？
Think of it as a good investment of your time.
就当这是在有效投资你的时间吧
Well, well. Mrs. Kamogawa.
我的贵宾 鸭川大人
Thank you for all your help before, Mr. Kamiki.
神木先生 感谢你之前的帮忙
You asked of your faithful servant, and I delivered.
您召唤您忠实的仆从 我当然要全力以赴
You're still going on about that?
怎么还提那些啊？
Of course. A promise is a promise.
当然 承诺就是承诺
Please, come this way.
来 这边请
That's right.
对了
You have a store in Musashimurayama City, don't you?
鸭川大人在武藏村山市 有家店铺 对吧？
Yes, I do.
对
So, you don't want the transfer?
这么说来 你不想调任？
Just so you know, I'm the one who suggested you.
你得知道 是我推荐了你去纽约
You did?
是吗？
Why me?
为什么选我？
Because you care about others.
因为你关心他人
I care?
“关心”？
You've always been a brilliant worker,
你一直是个优秀的员工
but you were very corporate when it came to the customer.
但过去 每当涉及到客户 你总是非常公事公办
But then you transferred here.
后来你调来了这里
Now the people and the community are front and center of your mind.
如今 这里的人和这个社区 已经成了你心里最重要的事
You're a very well-rounded worker.
你成了一个面面俱到的多面手
Japan's not the only place in the world that needs workers like that.
我们不只在日本需要这样的员工
Why do you hesitate?
为何犹豫？
Because
因为
I want to get married.
我想结婚
So?
那又如何？
Who says you have to quit work once you get married?
谁说你结了婚就得辞职？
I know, but,
我知道 但…
he has to work here.
对方得在这里工作
Is he the type to think a woman belongs in the kitchen?
他是那种认为女人 婚后就该在厨房忙活的人吗？
I don't think so.
应该不是
But,
但…
I don't want to leave him.
我不想跟他分隔两地
I want to be with him.
我想待在他身边
At all times.
一直跟他在一起
So…
所以…
I'm very sorry, Ms. Aihara.
真的非常抱歉 爱原前辈
Who is it?
是谁？
What?
嗯？
Who's the lucky man?
那个结婚对象是谁？
Did I not tell you?
我没跟您说吗？
-Mr. Nagas-- -Not one more syllable.
-是永… -一个音节也别再多说
I'm going to propose.
我打算求婚
Oh, my gosh!
天啊
Yes!
太好了
What are you crying for?
你怎么还哭了？
Just look at you!
你自己也没好到哪去
I mean, we've known Saichi since he was a student.
我们从永濑学生那会就认识他了
Feels like it's my own--
他就像我自己的…
Oh, my gosh. Congratulations!
太好了 恭喜你
He's too direct! You'll fight, I just know it!
他太直白了 你们以后一定争吵不休
I know, but I still want to marry him.
我知道 但我还是想跟他结婚
He's Saichi Nagase. Honest to a fault.
他是过分诚实的永濑财地
I love that about him.
我非常喜欢他这点
You'll come crawling back.
你一定会哭着回来找我诉苦
I won't regret this.
我绝对不会后悔
Fine.
我明白了
I shall forever hold my peace.
我会永远搁置异议 保持沉默
I wish you all the very best.
祝你一切安好
Thank you.
谢谢
Tonight, we drink!
今夜 我们不醉不归
Yes!
好
-Cheers.
-干杯
This is such great news.
真是太好了
You're overreacting.
你们太夸张了
I'm not overreacting. I'm serious. Well done!
我没夸张 都是真心的 好样的
This is such great news!
这真是天大的喜讯
-Come on, stop it. -This is great! So great!
-好了 快别这样 -真好 太好了
This right here was a lifesaver for the project.
这东西是这项目的救命稻草
I need you to get that notebook for me.
我需要你帮我弄到那个笔记本
You lost a lot on crypto, right?
你玩加密货币输了不少吧？
Really. This is really great.
真的 真是太好了
What's this? Tokage?
哎哟？十影？
Don't often see you here. What's up?
难得在这里见到你 怎么了？
Come to celebrate the good news too?
你也来庆祝他的喜讯吗？
I feel like crap.
好难受
MUSASHIMURAYAMA WAREHOUSE PLAN MARCH 2018 ONWARDS
（武藏村山市仓库建设计划 2018年3月-）
MUSASHIMURAYAMA CITY, SAYAMA RESIDENCE
（武藏村山市 狭山宅邸）
Mr. Sayama.
狭山先生
AKIO SAYAMA JUNICHI, NATSUMI &amp; SHOTA SAYAMA
（狭山纯一、夏石、将太 狭山昭雄）
You are one of the leaseholders of the idle cropland in Musashimurayama?
您是武藏村山 那片闲置农地的地权人之一吧？
Yes.
对
And you are a teacher.
您是老师
You teach social studies at Yaoki Daini Middle School.
在八起第二中学教社会科学
JUNICHI SAYAMA MIDDLE SCHOOL TEACHER
（狭山纯一 中学老师）
How do you know all this?
你怎么会知道这些？
I have an acquaintance.
从一位旧识那里听说的
I may be preaching to the choir when I say this,
接下来的话可能有些明知故问
but are you familiar with the words of one former Prime Minister?
但您是否知道 前首相田中角荣说过一句话？
Former Prime Minister?
田中角荣？
Kakuei Tanaka was a serial con man, and they say this was his favorite saying.
他是个连环骗子 据说这是他最爱的一句话
"Give a womanizer a woman, and a miser his money.
“对方好色就给他女人 好财就给他钱财
If a man is neither,
若两者皆不能投其所好
give yourself as his honey."
就把自己献给他”
So, what's your vice?
所以 您“好”什么？
A FEW DAYS LATER
（数日后）
PURCHASE AND SALE AGREEMENT OF REAL ESTATE
（房地产买卖合同）
NOTICE OF TERMINATION OF CONTRACT
（合同解除通知书）
NOTIFIER - JUNICHI SAYAMA
（通知人 狭山纯一）
Mr. Sayama, wait. Please.
狭山先生 且慢
What do you mean you're backing out now?
您现在要退出是什么意思？
I'm sorry, Mr. Nagase.
很抱歉 永濑先生
I'll pay double the deposit, but please, just cancel the contract.
我愿意支付双倍违约金 但请帮我取消合同
Man…
天
Is Mr. Sayama seriously pulling out?
狭山先生真要退出吗？
Looks like it. Mr. Nagase is trying to convince him otherwise.
是的 永濑前辈正在劝他改变主意
Wasn't Mr. Sayama's plot of land…
狭山先生的那块地好像…
right in the middle of the Musashimurayama project?
位于武藏村山项目的正中间？
That's right.
没错
What happens to the project if Mr. Sayama cancels his contract?
如果狭山先生取消合同 对项目会有什么影响？
It'd be game over for the project.
那么项目就将告吹
1738 - JUNICHI SAYAMA
（1738 狭山纯一）
Won't you please reconsider, Mr. Sayama?
狭山先生 请您再考虑一下好吗？
I've already thought about it.
我已经仔细想过了
I'm a middle school teacher.
我是中学老师
As a teacher, it's my job to think of the community.
为社区着想是我的责任
The community?
社区？
I have my students, and I have my son to think about.
我要为我的学生和儿子考虑
If a warehouse were to go up,
如果修建仓库
that'll mean more trucks, and that's a danger to the children.
将有大量卡车来往 对孩子们来说会很危险
I'm a man all about safety.
我是个安全至上的男人
If it's the safety aspects you're concerned about,
如果您顾虑的是安全方面
we went over that five years ago.
我们五年前就已经协商过了
-Did we? -We did! Multiple times.
-有吗？ -有 协商了很多次
And you know what you said?
狭山先生您当时说…
What did I say?
我说什么了？
You said…
您说…
"Safety doesn't satisfy a man's belly. Take me out for some fine sushi!"
“安全可填不饱肚子 带我去吃高级寿司”
And I took you, didn't I?
所以我照做了 不是吗？
I took you to a sushi place that takes bookings two years in advance.
我带您去了一家 需要提前两年预定的寿司店
Yes, but--
的确 但…
And that's not all.
不仅如此
We had white truffles from Italy,
我们还吃了来自意大利的白松露
fabled caviar from the Caspian Sea,
闻名天下的里海鱼子酱
and legendary grade-A foie gras!
还有顶级鹅肝
"Gourmet! Gourmet!" You begged and you bleated.
您一直喊着：“高级料理 下一道”
And I was there to ensure you had a good time!
当时是我陪着您 确保您吃得尽兴
And I hate foie gras!
哪怕我其实非常讨厌鹅肝
Well, anyway. I'd like to withdraw from this contract.
总之 我要解除这份合同
Wait. Mr. Sayama.
慢着 狭山先生
Damn it.
可恶
This must be Kamiki's doing.
一定是神木在搞鬼
It doesn't matter who did it.
谁在搞鬼并不重要
If this project falls through,
如果项目告吹
then our reputation will hit rock bottom.
我们的声誉将毁于一旦
I'll try talking to him again.
我会再找他谈谈
We've all worked long and hard on this project.
大家都为这项目努力了太久
We deserve to see it through.
我们理应看到它开花结果
I won't let it fall through.
我绝不会让它告吹
Mr. Tosaka.
社长
I'm a member of Tosaka Real Estate.
我也是登坂不动产的一员
Let me help too.
请让我也来帮忙吧
I may not have much to offer, but allow me to help where I can.
我可能帮不上太多 但请让我尽力而为吧
All right!
很好
Tsukishita, you go with Nagase
月下 你跟永濑一组
-and bring Mr. Sayama around! -Yes.
-一定要让狭山先生回心转意 -是
-Fujiwara and I will talk to the builder. -Okay.
-藤原和我去找建筑商协商 -好
As for the rest of you,
至于剩下的各位
make sure Minerva stays away from the other leaseholders.
一定要确保密涅瓦不动产 无法再接触其他地权人
-Okay. -We will.
-是
-Do we have a list? -Yes.
-我们有名单吗？ -有
Mr. Sayama's quite the gourmand, right?
狭山先生很爱美食 是吧？
Leave that to me.
包在我身上
Sure.
好
-Are you sure? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -对
LARGE-SCALE DEVELOPMENT REPRESENTATIVE
（大规模开发代表）
One of your leaseholders, Mr. Sayama,
您有一位叫狭山的地权人
has decided to sell his land to us instead.
已经决定把他的土地转卖给我们
Mr. Sayama's land is right in the middle of our project!
狭山那块地 位于我们项目的正中央
You are exactly right.
正是如此
As the builder's representative,
作为建筑商代表
I'm sure you're aware of just how valuable this piece of land is.
您一定知道这块地的价值
How much would you pay for it?
贵方愿意花多少钱购回呢？
Pay for it?
购回？
Your six-year-long project is finished without that one little plot of land.
没有那一小块地 你们筹备了六年的项目将宣告失败
That's going to upset a lot of people.
那一定会惹怒不少人
It's not up to me.
这事我做不了主
I'll be waiting for the correct answer.
那我静候您的佳音
YUMMY CAKES
（美味蛋糕）
I got the cake. I'm about to find a taxi.
我买到蛋糕了 马上打车过去
Yes.
好
Mr. Kiriyama?
桐山先生？
Mr. Sayama?
狭山先生？
Why?
什么情况？
Oh, no.
不会吧
Can I help you?
有事吗？
Are you Mr. Akio Sayama, Mr. Junichi Sayama's father?
您是狭山先生的父亲 狭山昭雄先生吗？
I am.
我是
Nice to see you again.
很高兴又见面了
I'm Saichi Nagase from Tosaka Real Estate.
我是登坂不动产的永濑财地
I came to visit six years ago about purchasing your plot of land.
六年前 我来拜访过 跟您商量购买土地的事
Mr. Nagase.
永濑先生
AKIO SAYAMA MR. SAYAMA'S FATHER
（狭山昭雄 纯一之父）
So, can I help you?
这次有何贵干？
Mr. Sayama suddenly said he didn't want to sell us the land.
其实是因为 狭山先生突然说不想把地卖给我们了
Why'd he say that?
为何？
He says he's concerned for the safety of the children and the community.
他说担心孩子们和社区的安全
He really said that?
他真那么说吗？
Yes.
是的
Well, the land's his.
那块地如今在他名下
I gave it to him to do with as he wishes.
我已经交给了他 他想怎么处理都行
You'll need to discuss it with him.
你得找他谈
Do you think I'm daft?
你当我傻吗？
Well, no.
没有
What do you want?
你想怎样？
That man you were with before,
刚才跟您在一起的那位
that was Mr. Sayama, right?
是狭山先生吧？
He's one of the leaseholders in a Tosaka Real Estate project.
他是登坂不动产一个项目中的地权人
Now all of a sudden he wants to cancel his contract with us.
现在突然想取消跟我们的合同
Why would someone like that be talking to you?
说起来 他为何会联系桐山先生呢？
It's none of your business.
与你无关
I hear large-scale developments like ours
我听说 像我们这次这样的 大规模开发项目
are literal gold mines to brokers such as yourself.
对您这样的自由中介来说如同金矿
You're not trying to stab us in the back, are you?
难道桐山先生想背刺我们吗？
And what if I am?
如果是呢？
Then you're dead to me.
我绝不允许
If you're out to steal what Mr. Tosaka and Mr. Nagase have worked so hard for…
社长和永濑前辈为此付出了巨大努力 如果你想抢走…
then you are dead to me.
我绝对不允许
So you waited until nightfall and you still never got to see him?
然而 你等到天黑也没能见到狭山？
Hopefully you get to see him tomorrow.
希望你明天能见到他
No matter how long it takes, I'll keep showing up every single day.
不管要等多久 我每天都会去
You really like your job, don't you?
永濑真的很热爱自己的工作吧？
I'm enjoying it even more lately.
最近甚至越来越享受其中了
Before I was only ever thinking about ways to make more money.
以前我一心只想着多赚钱
What changed?
有什么不一样了吗？
I guess I realized
我好像明白了
my job is to help other people.
我的工作其实是帮助他人
To help people?
帮助他人？
I get to have such a positive impact. Wouldn't you agree?
我能为他人带去幸福 不是吗？
Positive impact?
幸福？
Mr. Sayama, can we talk?
狭山先生 我们能谈谈吗？
Not you again.
怎么又是你们？
We only need a moment of your time. I bought you this--
我们只需占用您一点时间 我给您买了这个…
I don't want it. Go away.
我不要 赶紧走
-Mr. Sayama.
-狭山先生
Just a moment of your time--
只占用您一小会…
Can't believe this…
真要命
You came all this way.
你大老远跑过来
Why won't you say anything?
怎么一言不发？
Well, I…
我…
Shall I take a guess
需要我猜猜吗？
at why you're here?
你来这里的原因
What?
嗯？
There's something you want to ask me,
你有事想问我
but you don't know how to bring it up.
但不知该如何开口
You're wondering even whether you should raise it with me.
你甚至不确定 是否该找我这个奶奶商量
How'd you guess?
您怎么猜到的？
It's written all over your face.
你脸上都写着呢
What?
嗯？
Kento.
健人
Have you heard of this saying?
你有没有听过一句老话？
"If you want to be happy for a day,
“若想开心一天
visit the barber.
就去理发
If you want to be happy for a week,
想开心一周
buy a car."
就去买车”
I know the one.
我知道这个
"If you want to be happy for a month,
“若想开心一个月
marry a wife.
就去娶妻
If you want to be happy for a year,
想开心一年
buy a house."
就去买房”
-Isn't that right? -Yes.
-对吧？ -没错
Mr. Nagase's always saying that one.
永濑先生总念叨这些
There's more to it.
其实这话还有下文
There's more?
下文？
"If you want to be happy all your life,
“若想开心一辈子
be an honest man."
就做个正直的人”
You see?
懂了吗？
What is this?
什么意思？
I guess
看来
I'm now a man who cannot tell a lie.
我现在也成了无法说谎的人
Come over all you want. I won't change my mind.
你尽管来吧 我不会改变主意
Please, Mr. Sayama.
拜托了
Our six-year-long project will be for naught if you don't sell to us.
如果狭山先生您不肯卖地给我们 那我们六年的努力将付之东流
Why should I care?
那种事与我何干？
You shouldn't even be building a giant warehouse there anyway.
你们本就不该在那里修建巨型仓库
Why not?
为何不该？
I told you.
我说过了
All those trucks coming in and out are a danger to the children.
那么多卡车进进出出 对孩子们来说很危险
It's our job as teachers to look out for the children.
我们当老师的 有责任照顾好孩子们
-Your job. -Yes.
-“责任” -对
I think that's very noble of you…
您真是高尚…
but I don't buy it for a second.
可我一秒都不相信
What an odd thing to say for a money-grubbing teacher like you!
你这种贪财的老师说出这种话 也太奇怪了
What?
什么？
You don't care about the kids.
你根本不关心孩子们
Money, money, money. You care about the money!
钱钱钱 你心里只有钱
Of course, I like money too.
当然 我也爱钱
Truth be told, six years ago when we were in negotiations,
实话跟您说吧 六年前 我们协商时
I was nothing but lip service in order to close a contract.
我为了达成交易 什么话都敢说
Because you know what I wanted? Money!
知道为什么吗？因为我只想赚钱
You get it then. So lay off my back!
那你就该明白 别再来烦我了
But now I'm different.
可我现在不一样了
Now I'm asking you to think about the land.
现在我想请您考虑下那片土地
The land?
那片土地？
Yes.
对
Well, well. Nagase.
永濑
What are you doing here?
你来这里干什么？
Kamiki.
神木
Mr. Sayama, do not fall prey to this man's wheedling.
狭山先生 别被这家伙的花言巧语迷惑
I've been speaking with the builder's representative.
我最近一直在跟建筑商代表协商
They're willing to pay whatever it takes to purchase your land.
他们愿意不惜代价购买狭山先生的地
I have a blank check right here.
我已经带来了银行支票簿
Put down whatever you like.
价格任您填写
CHECK
（支票）
100 million?
一亿如何？
MASATO IKARUGA MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不动产 社长 鵤圣人）
One billion?
或是十亿？
Put whatever you like.
想要多少 您尽管填写
Mr. Sayama.
狭山先生
I went and visited the land the other day.
我前几天去看了那片地
The number of residents using it as farming land is dropping fast.
在土地上进行农耕的居民在急剧减少
There's even less people compared to when I saw it six years ago.
跟我六年前看到的情况相比 现在更是少之又少
At this rate,
照这个速度发展下去
the land is only going to fall into further disrepair.
那片土地将更加荒芜
But a large warehouse,
但若能修建大型仓库
that'll create roads, draw new people, and bring in more taxes.
就能开通道路 吸引新人 并带来更多税收
It will revive the land.
能让土地复苏
Merely armchair speculation.
都是纸上谈兵
Nobody knows what the future might hold.
没人知道未来可能如何
Many warehouses built on vacant land
已经有许多修建在闲置土地上的仓库
have been left abandoned out of pure convenience.
由于使用不便而被弃用
And there are just as many success stories
但也有许多成功案例
where it brings a community together.
让社区变得更加团结
I can assure you, it'll be safe.
安全方面 我可以向您保证
Mr. Sayama.
狭山先生
Your parents were the ones who toiled that land, day in and day out.
您的父母曾在那片土地上 日复一日地劳作
That land raised you. It is a great treasure.
您也在那片土地上长大 它是一笔巨大的宝藏
I think you should let that treasure come back to life.
我认为您该让那宝藏起死回生
For the future.
为了您的儿子
Your son's, and all your students'.
也为了学生们的未来
Their future?
他们的未来？
Mr. Nagase, he's here.
永濑前辈 他来了
Why is my dad here?
我父亲怎么来了？
Mr. Sayama.
狭山先生
You figured we'd stop by to convince you again,
您知道我们会再来劝您
and so you told your father not to be here, didn't you?
所以让父亲别过来 对吗？
I think you did that because you have a guilty conscience.
我觉得您那么做 是因为您心中有愧
No, I don't.
才不是
Junichi.
纯一
I gave you that land.
我把那块地交给了你
So do with it what you will.
所以你想怎么处理都行
But let me say just one thing.
但我只说一句
You are a teacher,
你是老师
so you should never act unethically.
所以绝不该做出不道德之事
Do this for your son.
你得为你的儿子
Be a father who holds his head high.
做一个挺胸做人的父亲
Looks like Mr. Sayama changed his mind.
看来狭山先生改变主意了
Thanks to you.
多亏了你
I only did what I felt was right.
我只是做了自己觉得正确的事
Right.
原来如此
By the way…
对了
Sakura Tsukishita.
月下咲良…
If you're out to steal what Mr. Tosaka and Mr. Nagase have worked so hard for…
社长和永濑前辈为此付出了巨大努力 如果你想抢走…
then you are dead to me.
我绝对不允许
She's become a feisty one.
她变得很有锋芒了
She has, hasn't she?
可不是吗？
This is the first time you've called me out somewhere.
这是你第一次叫我出来
I'd like to ask you something.
我想问你件事
Sure, but I should say
没问题 但我得说
we've already finalized everything with Mr. Sayama.
我们已经跟狭山先生敲定了一切
I know you have.
我知道
I've given up on that.
那件事我已经放弃了
"Be a father who can hold his head high for his son."
“做一个挺胸做人的父亲”
Those words struck me.
昭雄先生那句话点醒了我
Remember what you said?
还记得你说过什么吗？
You said you'd found something more important than coming in first.
你说找到了比当第一更重要的事
What was it?
到底是什么？
It's been on my mind all month.
我整个月都在纠结此事
So much so that I lost to Ms. Hanasawa and dropped to second place.
甚至输给花泽 落到了第二名
I don't get it.
我不明白
I can't think of anything.
想不到任何答案
What is more important
究竟有什么
than coming in first?
比当第一更重要？
I believe
我认为是…
it's bringing joy to others.
为他人带去幸福
Whether I come in first or not,
无论我是否能当第一
just one positive impact
只要能为一个人带去幸福
is enough to keep me happy.
就足以让我开心
That's how I see it now.
这就是我现在的看法
Bringing joy to others.
为他人带去幸福
You can change.
神木你也可以改变
I believe in you.
我相信你
Shota?
翔太？
Kaori?
香织？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Daddy couldn't come in first.
爸爸没能当第一
I promise next time…
我保证下次…
Shota.
翔太
Wait. Don't go!
等等 别走
Look, Shota. You remember the dance?
快看 翔太 还记得这舞步吗？
Come on, Shota. Let's dance.
来啊 翔太 我们跳舞
Don't go, Shota.
别走啊 翔太
Shota!
翔太
Come dance with Daddy.
跟爸爸跳舞啊
Please, Shota!
拜托 翔太
Hey, do that again!
再跳一次吧
Daddy, do it again.
爸爸 再跳一次
I like it!
我喜欢
Kamiki?
神木？
Won't you please dance again, sir?
叔叔 能再跳一次吗？
No, Hokuto.
北斗 别闹
Sorry.
抱歉
You went like this.
您刚才是这么跳的
What? What kind of dance is that?
嗯？那是什么舞步？
You do it, Mama.
妈妈来跳跳看
I can't dance.
妈妈不会跳舞
What?
嗯？
That's so cool.
好厉害
Like this?
是这样吗？
Sorry about him.
失礼了
Mr. Nagase.
永濑前辈
It's almost time.
差不多到时间了
-Okay. -Here.
-好 -嗯
What?
嗯？
Excuse us, we have work to do.
抱歉 我们还有工作
I'm here for Mr. Nagase.
我来找永濑
Not for the newbie.
与菜鸟无关
Typical. Always looking down on people.
一如既往 看不起别人
Tsukishita's not a newbie anymore.
月下已经不是菜鸟了
She's a brilliant coworker
她是位优秀的同僚
and she's a valued partner of mine.
是我珍贵的搭档
What he said.
没错
Excuse us.
失陪了
Let's go.
我们走
Come work for me.
来为我工作吧
You can name your price.
任你开价
You can offer all the money in the world,
哪怕你出金山银山
but I'll still never work for you.
我也不会为你工作
I like where I work.
我喜欢这家公司
I like the people I work with.
喜欢一起工作的同事
That's the only reason.
这是唯一的理由
You'll regret that answer.
我一定会让你后悔今天的回答
I'll make sure of it.
做好准备吧
I've been offered a transfer to New York, and I'm going to take it.
公司要调我去纽约 我打算接受
New York?
纽约？
Since spending time with you,
跟永濑一起生活的这段时间
my attitude towards my work has changed.
让我对工作的态度发生了转变
I want to be honest with people,
我想正直待人
and I want to face their challenges with passion.
也想充满热情地面对他们的挑战
I know I can help
我知道
individuals and their families
我能帮助人们和他们的家人
and so many others.
还有千千万万的其他人
That's what I want to do with my work.
我想这样工作
I know I'll regret this if I don't do it now.
如果现在放弃 我今后一定会后悔
I just know it.
我确定
So,
所以
I'm going to New York.
我要去纽约
Minami?
榎本
Yes?
嗯？
I think it's a great idea--
我觉得这个想法非常了不起…
But to be honest, I'm really gonna miss you!
但我必须承认 我一定会非常想念你
I've loved our meals together and chatting together.
我喜欢跟你一起吃饭、聊天
So I hope you do well over there so you can come back soon!
所以我希望你在那边好好干 早日归来
Don't worry.
放心吧
For, you see…
你看…
I shall extend your short list period.
我要延长你的最终考察期
Extend?
延长？
You will report to me on your day, every day, while I'm in New York.
我在纽约期间 你要每天向我汇报
JAPAN TIME 21:00 - 21:30 NY TIME 8:00 - 8:30
（日本时间 纽约时间）
I may also drop in from time to time to ensure you continue living up to standard.
我也可能时不时回来 确保你按照标准生活
Wait, this is even more demanding!
等等 这比以前更难了
Dear god…
天
Of course it is, you're a dirty perv!
当然要更难 你这老变态
Really?
嗯？
Every day?
每天？
Minami. I've been waiting for this, Minami.
榎本 这一刻我等了好久
G'bye!
再见
Minami!
榎本？
Really?
真的吗？
She'll have hot guys coming out the wazoo for her in New York.
她在纽约会遇到遍地帅哥
She is very pretty.
美波小姐真的很漂亮
She is.
可不是吗
What's this? I'm getting palpitations.
你们这是干什么？我快心梗了
Nagase. Come.
永濑 来
-Let us drink. -Okay.
-我们喝一杯 -好
Lost loves are best washed away with a drink.
失恋最好借酒消愁
-I wasn't dumped-- -No.
-我没失恋… -得了吧
-I'm Nagase. "The" Saichi Nagase. -It's okay, Mr. Nagase.
-我可是大名鼎鼎的永濑 -没事的 永濑前辈
-I'm "the" Saichi Nagase. -Relax.
-永濑财地的“永濑” -放松
"The" Saichi Nagase? "The"?
大名鼎鼎好吗？
-It's okay. -That's lame.
-没事的 -真糟糕
Mr. Nagase.
永濑
-Mr. Ishida is here to see you. -Mr. Ishida?
-石田先生找你 -石田先生？
He says he's figured out how to break the curse?
他说什么…知道怎么解除诅咒了？
-Hey! -Nagase, wait!
-棒 -永濑 等等
For real?
真的吗？
-Did you really figure it out? -What?
-您真的搞清楚了吗？ -嗯？
Do you really know how to break the curse?
您真的知道如何解除诅咒了吗？
Yeah. I do.
啊…真的
Please, tell me!
请告诉我
Once it's broken, that wind will never come back.
一旦解除就永远无法恢复
You all right with that?
你能接受吗？
Never again?
永远？
Yep. So, what'll it be?
对 如何？
Are you still upset?
你还在郁闷吗？
Should I tell you?
该不该告诉你呢？
You know, I've actually been cursed.
其实 我被诅咒了
A gust of wind would hit me whenever I tried to tell a lie
只要我想说谎 就会有一阵强风袭来
and I'd be forced to tell the truth.
我就会被迫说出真话
Are you surprised?
惊讶吗？
Seriously?
救命
What?
啊？
You really are hopeless.
救命啊
What are you even on about?
你在胡说八道什么呢？
Quit your blabbering, we've got work to do!
别叽叽歪歪了 我们还有工作呢 赶紧
But it's the truth.
可这是真的
Thank you.
我开动了
Wow, that's good.
真好吃
You sure are a reliable lot.
你们这帮家伙还真靠谱
Thank you.
谢谢
I know I can retire whenever I like because of them.
有他们在 我知道自己随时都能放心退休
Can't let you do that.
那可不行
Why not?
嗯？
You don't get to quit until I quit making confectionery.
只要我还做一天和菓子 你就一天不能退休
Lovely spring weather.
春天真美好啊
It sure is.
确实
-What did you say, Tsukishita? -Come on. Let's go.
-月下 你刚才说什么？ -快走
-You called me hopeless? -Yes, and?
-居然喊救命？ -对 不行吗？
I swear I'm telling you the truth.
我发誓 我说的是实话
What do you mean?
到底什么意思？
I'm telling you a wind makes me tell the truth.
真的 会有一阵风逼我说出实话
-What do you have there? -I win.
-你中邪了吗？ -我赢了
Why are you running so fast? Wait!
你跑那么快干什么？等等
THE HONEST REALTOR 2 FINAL EPISODE
电视剧名：正直不动产2
HONEST REALTOR FOREVER
第10集：永远的正直不动产